<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>The Lion</title>
	<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
	<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2020-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Updates avalanche</title>
		<published>2020-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2020-10-16/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2020-10-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh boy, it&#x27;s been a long time. I remade the site from scratch, how will things be going forward?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m not good at introductions so let&#x27;s just go, please.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-is-the-website-made-now&quot;&gt;How is the website made now?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caved in! I am now using Zola and no longer on Neocities as a result because of fancy shenanigans 
that don&#x27;t work there, I think. I might try again at a later date. So, until further disappearance, I&#x27;m here on Codeberg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-s-all-the-pictures&quot;&gt;Where&#x27;s all the pictures?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#x27;re gone, they were never really used meaningfully. They were just me trying to make things look cool and well, there was no
clear theme or style and it started to bother me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-s-the-mistakes-section&quot;&gt;Where&#x27;s the mistakes section?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It never went anywhere with mind being scared, honestly. I think it&#x27;s better if I fill it in with more current mistakes than charging
it with the past, it&#x27;s easier for me and probably makes more sense for you. Sorry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-s-the-recommendations&quot;&gt;Where&#x27;s the recommendations?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are no longer there, I might try to re-implement them but I think I&#x27;d rather try to integrate it better in the text. We&#x27;ll see how that goes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-i-still-follow-the-atom-feed&quot;&gt;Can I still follow the Atom feed?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! Although, it&#x27;s no longer at the same place so sorry about that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-the-website-mit-now&quot;&gt;Why is the website MIT now?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I didn&#x27;t really wanna build everything from scratch so I took Zola-Paper and modified it and will continue to do so but it means I&#x27;m under that license now 
which I suppose isn&#x27;t so bad for this small website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;waaaa-where-are-all-the-semantics&quot;&gt;Waaaa, where are all the semantics?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#x27;re coming back, I still need to tame the beast more and I&#x27;ll be implementing them more and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-am-i-going-to-do-with-this-site-going-forward&quot;&gt;What am I going to do with this site going forward?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ll be trying to post more often, avoiding meta posts... like this one, for instance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, check &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lionirdeadman.codeberg.page&#x2F;2020-10-15&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the last post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I think it was interresting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Food for thought : Social media sent information back to the dark ages</title>
		<published>2020-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2020-10-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2020-10-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This might sound quite ridiculous but let me explain how I came to this conclusion by describing three eras. Mind you, this is a think piece, not a research so take that as you will.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m not really good at history to be honest so it&#x27;s likely I&#x27;ll be wrong in some way but I&#x27;ll be rather vague.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dark-ages&quot;&gt;The Dark Ages&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&#x27;s look back before information was free. During those times, the information was given by authorities (This might&#x27;ve been governments or the Church).
Why is this important? Simply put, you weren&#x27;t alone nor on an equal field. If you were to criticise something in the public, you&#x27;d likely be exiled therefore you
had to trust them to tell the truth and since this was shared knowledge and there were no alternatives, you were just left with that. There was no action.
Until the press and literacy started growing...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-renaissance&quot;&gt;The Renaissance&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the invention of the printer is what started it all. With this, information wasn&#x27;t given by authority anymore, it was not public so it was entirely your choice
if you decided to believe it or criticize it. That&#x27;s not to say that this was always easy but it could be done. Critical thinking sprouting and it all went uphill
from there. Thoughts could finally be distributed freely. Or could they?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-fall&quot;&gt;The Fall&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the internet, everyone can say anything! This is great, information can be shared more quickly than ever and with little costs compared to the old days of
the press. But then something happens, social media is born. At first, this only made things better to the eyes of people, they could easily discuss news and share it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is great, isn&#x27;t it? What&#x27;s the problem? People stopped going to the news for information, they&#x27;d just see what people were sharing. There&#x27;s nothing wrong with that?
Social media became the gateway to information. People started reading the headlines and discussing the information from there. The existance of embeds was the start of the end.
You&#x27;d likely not see who made the article you skimmed, you&#x27;d be more interrested in the discussions after this is social media. It&#x27;s all about your friends.. or is it now?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By trying to keep people entertained on their websites to generate income, social media created another problem : the algorithmic feed. Now, with the rise of social media, they realised
they wanted to keep you hooked in and so they created the algorithmic feed. At first, it probably encouraged discussions but with time, it encouraged radicalisation,
misinformation and yellow journalism.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woah woah, you&#x27;re going to fast, why would it do that? Well, first, radicalisation because people like to see what they like and if they don&#x27;t like it, it will lead to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;xkcd.com&#x2F;386&#x2F;&quot;&gt;xkcd #386&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
which the algorithm will just see as the article being &lt;em&gt;engaging&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Why misinformation? For the same as radicalisation, it just pays. Now, yellow journalism? Simple, headlines
go viral and then you&#x27;ll have more visitors. Wait, why do visitors matter? Well, certain newspapers turned to advertising too so they need the clicks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#x27;s how we&#x27;re here where information is free but misinformation reigns supreme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-we-do&quot;&gt;What can we do?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for leaving you on a down, I&#x27;ll be exploring this in a future article where I plan to talk about it more in depth. As the title suggests,
you can take that time to think about it, yeah? I promise I&#x27;ll answer soon (and update this post as a result).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Semantic web and rant</title>
		<published>2019-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-06-25/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-06-25/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, the semantic web, I came to it from being simply interresting in it because well, I thought it was good to make the computer 
understand my content and it also made HTML prettier in my eyes.. especially HTML5 semantic elements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s cool stuff and I learn along the way although, deeper semantics have left me deeply confused since their documentation is 
quite hard and there&#x27;s multiple implementations so for now, I decided to leave it at that and use simple semantics for the most part.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things like, the details element below, the figure element to put captions and picture elements together, the time element to make the 
time machine-readeable making that data potentially useful for research, the nav element for navigation elements, all these kind of things 
which make parsing much easier than a bajillion div elements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that brought me to well, the most common use for machine-readeable semantics -- Search. By far, search is what needs the most semantics 
to make the results appropriate. That lead me to changing my robots.txt to allow crawling of certain parts which was fairly straight forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I thought sitemap could be nice to allow it more easily and then since I had no feedback on those changes, I took my helmet and braced 
Google&#x27;s search console which is.. painful, there&#x27;s delays everywhere, you need to verify you own the website, you need to make sure your results 
look fine which will require even more waiting... then yesterday, I realised something terrible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain pages which I didn&#x27;t allow to be crawled were indexed, there was no way to remove it from any interface nor a hint to tell me so then 
I talked to a friend about it and he linked me something that made me very mad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that these settings can be read and followed only if crawlers are allowed to access the pages that include these settings. 
The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;robots&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;noindex&amp;quot; &#x2F;&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; tag or directive applies to search engine crawlers. To block non-search crawlers, such as AdsBot-Google, 
you might need to add directives targeted to the specific crawler (for example, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;AdsBot-Google&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;noindex&amp;quot; &#x2F;&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;). -&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developers.google.com&#x2F;search&#x2F;reference&#x2F;robots_meta_tag&quot;&gt;Google&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this non-standard is really annoying. Not only does Google not see that not Crawling should equate in non-indexing but their solution to make 
the difference is a standard that they don&#x27;t even follow all the time, they say it only applies to search-engine bots.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that a problem? Indexing and crawling is one of the most basic flows of requests so when you can&#x27;t have a simple opt-out from all of them, 
you&#x27;ll end up with unwanted traffic and&#x2F;or a million meta tags to control it and that just makes me terribly mad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone at W3C or at Google reads this, please standardize a sane system for indexing and crawling. Robots.txt is not standardized so that can be painful 
to deal with and the meta robots tag doesn&#x27;t have a simple catch-all nor is it standardized either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Flexbox and more changes</title>
		<published>2019-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-06-18/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-06-18/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, just last week I was saying a bunch of changes I had made, well, this is not gonna be as long, it&#x27;s just some little updates.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-layout-again&quot;&gt;New layout (again)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, as you see, and as you probably saw to see this article. A new tweak for the layout, on desktops, you get more space used which is pretty good, really. I&#x27;m not sure how I like how it messes a little bit with how linear it was but it works and it&#x27;s still quite easy to manage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;related-pages&quot;&gt;Related pages&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m not sure what to say, I&#x27;m putting articles at the bottom of articles so people can discover new content from other people or my older content. Kind of similar to webrings but well, more curated in a way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mistakes&quot;&gt;Mistakes&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m quite scared and stressed about this but I do want to let it out. It&#x27;ll take time and courage but I&#x27;ll do it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-appropriate-links&quot;&gt;More appropriate links&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old links will be broken, sorry about that but I think the new ones better fit the content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I&#x27;ll try to stop redesigning so much and creating so much meta content. Sorry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Time for some change!</title>
		<published>2019-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-06-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-06-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&#x27;ve not updated this blog in a while but in the last few days I&#x27;ve updated it a bunch! So here&#x27;s some of the key changes from this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;biggest-change-probably-no-more-comments&quot;&gt;Biggest change probably : No more comments!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you might&#x27;ve thought it was about toxicity in comments or something about the ethics of it... It wasn&#x27;t used much either or well, I should say, I never saw it being used.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But well, it&#x27;s a lot simpler than that, the service seems to be no more. I contacted the admin and there was no response, it&#x27;s possible that the email service is also dead but well, it&#x27;s gone for now atleast.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;licensing&quot;&gt;Licensing&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did quite a bit of changes relating to work licenses, I already had the code under AGPLv3 as per my blog post but well, I have more changes.
Proper license notice for artwork&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now all of the artwork I use has the license terms and a link to the source for attribution! The github also has LICENSES files to make this easier for those who are seeing from there. I&#x27;m pretty happy with how that looks too.
Licensing my text as CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now all of the text is under CC BY-SA 4.0 which is noted at the end of each article so this change is pretty self-explanatory..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-styling&quot;&gt;New styling&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve done some few changes with the design, the posts page is more minimalist and more similar to the mobile view, I like it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have seen too, there&#x27;s a dark theme too! It works using &amp;quot;prefers-color-scheme: dark&amp;quot; which Safari, Chromium and Firefox respect based on your operating system settings or an internal setting&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s also new navigation changes which can be seen at the top for easier than before way to switch views.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;metadata-changes&quot;&gt;Metadata changes&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when websites need to embed the website, we give them the usual web author and description, we give OpenGraph metadata and Twitter metadata which should let them to have good embeds and previews for the content!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;switch-to-webp&quot;&gt;Switch to Webp&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put all the pictures from .pngs and .jpgs to .webps which reduced the size from there over five times (432kb from 2.9mb)!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Reponse to GNOME critique</title>
		<published>2019-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-05-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2019-05-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ll be answering the points one at a time as a gnome user so strap on for the ride, it&#x27;s gonna be a long one. I&#x27;d highly recommend reading their post first so you can see the points which I&#x27;m adressing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-a-desktop-that-does-nothing&quot;&gt;1. A Desktop that does nothing&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s part of the design, get everything out of the way. That&#x27;s also why the workplace switcher isn&#x27;t shown unless you press the user key. Maximimize screen real estate while still offering the features in a coherent manner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-barely-functional-status-bar&quot;&gt;2. Barely functional status bar&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound is the exception because most people will simply use the keyboard keys unlike Wi-Fi or Bluetooth where that&#x27;s not an option? That makes sense to me, I&#x27;m not sure what&#x27;s off about this&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-connecting-to-a-wi-fi-network-is-too-many-steps&quot;&gt;a. Connecting to a Wi-Fi network is too many steps&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my understanding, this is done to avoid having an overly long sub-menu but still being able to quickly change networks (as opposed to opening the settings app which would be more work) It&#x27;s a compromise made by design&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;b-no-battery-percentage-option&quot;&gt;b. No battery percentage option&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry is misleading at best, you yourself admit that the option exists in Gnome Tweaks I&#x27;ll explain why Gnome Tweaks is a good thing later ;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;c-no-app-indicators&quot;&gt;c. No app indicators&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is a little more complicated to explain. It&#x27;s a good thing. Bear with me now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, the old format was the one supported by TopIcons, it&#x27;s quite poor due to the API and so, they removed support for that old API.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Okay but I want them!&amp;quot; I hear you say, that&#x27;s why Ubuntu made the extension with a newer and better API which people actually support unlike what you lead people to believe when you say &amp;quot;Even if a better implementation may exist, it needs to be understood and accepted that cross-platform apps are unlikely to create indicators specific to the Linux Desktop, a marketshare of less than 5%.&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Okay well, why isn&#x27;t that in GNOME?&amp;quot;, well, it&#x27;s relatively new for one and well, it&#x27;s more effort to maintain the more options you give but of course, that&#x27;s entirely the reason why it&#x27;s not done, it&#x27;s also possibly because of design decisions&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#x27;s where you comment on the GNOME-styled &amp;quot;Fragments&amp;quot; torrent client come in, that&#x27;s the design that GNOME seems to want, &amp;quot;if you want your program to run, you should leave it open&amp;quot;, and you might say that&#x27;s terrible but here&#x27;s the thing, GNOME is a very keyboard-based (more on that in a second) and uses Workspaces quite heavily so what you&#x27;d do is.. use them to put background programs if you don&#x27;t currently need them or they&#x27;re done for a specific &amp;quot;work&amp;quot; environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So about the keyboard oriented design of this anti-feature. What this effectively means is that you can use natural keyboard bindings to get to your application instead of using your cursor to get to the icon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the intrusivity of the notifications, I hear you, I&#x27;d personally want a do-not-disturb feature to block the peeking as Pop!_OS provides, I think that&#x27;s the best way to go about this issue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;d-no-suspend-button&quot;&gt;d. No suspend button&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that&#x27;s not great design and should be fixed, I agree.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-deceiving-app-drawer&quot;&gt;3. Deceiving app drawer&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You bundled things together here but I&#x27;ll try to stay coherent in my response. First of all, keyboard shortcuts should be known, they&#x27;re all in the settings if it really bothered anyone to have to click the application drawer icon in the first place... It&#x27;s really the first time I hear this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the truncated names, I don&#x27;t really think this as an issue considering the icons are also shown but as you said, it&#x27;s a WIP which will be done eventually for those that are bothered by it&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The folder issue is real, I&#x27;ll give you that but software handling it after a little of grumble works relatively well I would say.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-unnecessary-notifications&quot;&gt;4. Unnecessary notifications&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s done by design, windows are not meant to grab focus on gnome automatically, this can be annoying if you start an application then it just decides &amp;quot;lol, you were doing something? Well, I don&#x27;t care, focus on me&amp;quot; and so it tells you that the application has sucessfully loaded in instead, I would not expect this to change. Use the extension if you want to be annoyed&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-barebones-file-manager&quot;&gt;5. Barebones file manager&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-can-t-create-new-document-from-the-context-menu&quot;&gt;a. Can’t create new document from the context menu&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s in the help documents, maybe use them. Although a default for a blank file might be useful. I&#x27;m not sure how you would want this to be more &amp;quot;intuitive&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;b-confusing-action-buttons&quot;&gt;b. Confusing action buttons&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&#x27;ll be repeating myself more but it&#x27;s by design, tooltips are not elegant and you misconceived the hamburger menu as a setting menu while it&#x27;s an option menu since you wouldn&#x27;t put 30 bajillion options in the titlebar, that would be a cursed sight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;c-same-icons-for-different-file-types&quot;&gt;c. Same icons for different file types&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we not make an icon for literally every format on planet earth? Please. They&#x27;re similar formats, let&#x27;s use the same icon, spare my sanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;d-oh-the-file-picker&quot;&gt;d. Oh, the file picker!&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever thought that GNOME devs aren&#x27;t bothered by it and if people care so much about a stupid issue like that they could instead fix it rather than meme it? I think it&#x27;s quite an hostile mentality to expect people to work on everything and then complain and meme the issue rather than trying to fix it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;e-non-discoverable-way-to-bookmark-folders&quot;&gt;e. Non-discoverable way to bookmark folders&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next thing you&#x27;re gonna tell me that menubars are not intuitive and as per the issue you filed, we would like to not duplicate that UI since it&#x27;s frankly not very useful to do so and just more clutter... and GNOME tries to avoid exactly that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-document-viewer-pdf-reader-with-no-tabs&quot;&gt;6. Document viewer (PDF reader) with no tabs!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developer of the application doesn&#x27;t want this by design. If you don&#x27;t like it, there are other applications which you can use. Please don&#x27;t force people to do things that they don&#x27;t want because &amp;quot;People want it!&amp;quot;. Thank you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-two-photo-viewing-apps&quot;&gt;7. Two photo viewing apps&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While yes, you could dislike that. There is a clear distinction between the two and maybe I don&#x27;t want &amp;quot;GNOME Photos&amp;quot; to manage my photos but rather another photo manager but I still want a lightweight option like &amp;quot;Eye of Gnome&amp;quot; to view my pictures (which is what I do if you were wondering).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s kind of interesting how you fight to get more options unless when you personally find it inconvenient..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-can-t-find-my-settings&quot;&gt;8. Can’t find my settings&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&#x27;ll hate this part.. but here we go.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-undiscoverable-settings&quot;&gt;a. Undiscoverable settings&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncommon things are put behind 3 dot menus, who would&#x27;ve thought, right?..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, while you have ample of space, it&#x27;s worth mentioning that most people can access more than 3 access points meaning there isn&#x27;t as much place as you&#x27;d think.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;b-can-t-set-a-custom-wallpaper&quot;&gt;b. Can’t set a custom wallpaper&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except you can and you just said so.. sure, a file picker would be nice but what you&#x27;re saying is very misleading&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;c-tweaks-app-that-shouldn-t-exist&quot;&gt;c. Tweaks app that shouldn’t exist&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew this was gonna happen... why..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so, yes, some options could be changed over. However, this is a design decision.. So, we don&#x27;t want the clusterfuck of options from KDE so we put it in another application so those things are still available while not overwhelming the user which uses the settings application.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&#x27;s also another thing to consider, some of those settings are not entirely safe to use so we might not want them to be as easy to access as all the other options to avoid the user breaking their system. Some options which could result in that include : Scaling, Themes, Extensions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR : It&#x27;s a compromise between flexibility and stability&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, gnome settings is more so DE-agnostic being that I could use all of the settings in there in another environment, while with Tweaks, that&#x27;s not the case.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-software-center&quot;&gt;9. Software Center&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just shown in the updates menu where you would expect them to be... Also, if they don&#x27;t show up there, it&#x27;s your distro&#x27;s fault
Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I appreciate the time you&#x27;ve taken to state your points, I highly disagree and hope you can understand my points. Thanks for reading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Crawling back to Github...</title>
		<published>2018-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-09-29/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-09-29/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m really sad. My code contributions have been quite low and I haven&#x27;t worked as much as I wish I did, my code&#x27;s been relatively untouched in the last months even though I need to modify it. But I&#x27;m also sad that my switch to Gitlab has not been as smooth as I wish it had been.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, the most frustrating part is how Gitlab handles watching and the lack of notifications unlike Github. This makes me watch my repositories manually most of the time which is quite frustrating. I really hope they work on this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would switch to something which does have notifications like for example &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gitbucket.github.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gitbucket&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but I have no hosting place to do this so it&#x27;s an impossibility at the moment. Maybe somebody else can offer it to me until I can use a VPS of my own&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hate to do this but notifications is something I really need out of my git platform. &lt;em&gt;sighs&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>This blog is AGPLv3!</title>
		<published>2018-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-05-21/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-05-21/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This whole blog&#x27;s source code is now licensed under AGPLv3, celebrate! Okay, the code is pretty crappy but that&#x27;s another story, hopefully it improves. Feel free to contribute!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may have broken some things with some of the changes I did but I think it&#x27;s okay. At least, when I tested locally, who knows what&#x27;ll happen once this thing goes on Neocities. Hopefully nothing otherwise that&#x27;d suck.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m still waiting for someone to actually comment on here which kind of stinks, I was hoping for people to do so! Who are those 1660 (at the time of this writing) people who saw this blog? What do they think? It really interests me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, that&#x27;s off-topic and so, I&#x27;ll just end this blog post here. Oh, right! The source code is here I may have a mirror on Github later, maybe, we&#x27;ll see if anyone wants me to do so. Well, that&#x27;s all I had to say, have a good day y&#x27;all!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Comments on my blog!</title>
		<published>2018-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-05-16/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-05-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay so I&#x27;ve been thinking about the best way for people reading my blog to contact me and I think I&#x27;ve found a solution which is pretty good.. comments! Okay, here&#x27;s why that&#x27;s a good way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-control&quot;&gt;1. Control&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the comment system in place, I don&#x27;t have a contact page but that&#x27;s good, you&#x27;ll just comment and put your email address and other ways I can contact you there and then I can contact you when I want, this means that I won&#x27;t risk getting spammed as much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-privacy&quot;&gt;2. Privacy&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The messages will not be public until I approve them so if you give me your contact information inside the comment, I&#x27;ll simply delete it and it&#x27;ll never be seen by other people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-just-comments&quot;&gt;3. Just.. comments!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you post a comment regarding the article &#x2F; blog post, I&#x27;ll approve it and people will be able to see it and reply to you. I think it&#x27;ll be really cool to see what you all think of this and it won&#x27;t feel like I&#x27;m talking to myself anymore, haha.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh! I almost forgot, the javascript and third-party service provider will not be loaded until you click the &amp;quot;Show comments&amp;quot; button so you can still read it without a third-party snooping on you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Friendships and honesty.</title>
		<published>2018-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-05-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-05-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that honesty is the foundation of any relationship. If you&#x27;re not honest with the people you talk to, you&#x27;re not yourself. You&#x27;re simply protraying someone which you&#x27;re not and therefore you&#x27;re actually creating a relationship in which two people, whom they&#x27;re not, are in a relationship.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Your friendship is therefore simply an illusion.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may say that your relationship is fine if you lie &#x27;sometimes&#x27; but this gives precendence for future dishonesty. If you lie because of shame, guilt or even fear, this relationship is toxic because it&#x27;s one in which you can&#x27;t express yourself. You are scared of the person with whom you&#x27;re supposedly friends with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you&#x27;re scared of that person, why would you be with them in the first place? You should be able to tell them anything without fear of consequences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may not want your friends to know certain things because you&#x27;re not comfortable and I think that&#x27;s perfectly normal but you shouldn&#x27;t be hiding it, you should simply tell them you don&#x27;t want to give them this information because you don&#x27;t have that kind of relationship with them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&#x27;m starting to go in circles so I&#x27;ll just end this post here.. Maybe I&#x27;m crazy to think this way, I&#x27;m not sure anymore..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why am I using Neocities?</title>
		<published>2018-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-04-27/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://lionirdeadman.codeberg.page/2018-04-27/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, for one, it&#x27;s free. &amp;quot;Okay, and?&amp;quot;, you may be saying. 
I don&#x27;t have the burden of hosting. I can simply code away the html and not worry about anything else..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This gives me freedom and peace of mind.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only that but since there&#x27;s no database or anything, just static files.
I&#x27;ve also further restricted myself by not using javascript (although that may change)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Because the web is bloated and it takes way too long to load most
pages and they&#x27;re just filled with ads, trackers, javascript and other crap.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&#x27;m just gonna post from here from time to time some decently-sized posts..
You can also subsribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lionirdeadman.codeberg.page&#x2F;atom.xml&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see whenever I post something
on here without making an account and stuff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
